07703464370

josie.a.newman@gmail.com josienewman.dev

Josie Newman Full-Stack Developer

In early 2021, I started learning to code as using some basic HTML & CSS was useful in my day-today job in communications, managing a WordPress CMS. I'd never done any programming before, but once I'd started learning JavaScript I instantly became hooked - I loved the creativity and the problemsolving it required. Fast-forward two years (and an awful lot of late nights studying later!), I'm now a fully-fledged developer, currently working full stack at a clean tech start-up.

TECH STACK

JavaScript

Python

Java

React.js

JQuery

Pyramid

Postgres

Figma

CURRENT ROLE

Junior Developer (Full-Stack)

Demand Logic · Nov 2021-Current

- · Worked on a complex software tool measuring the energy efficiency of large corporate buildings for some of the world's largest facilities management companies.
- Fixing bugs and adding new features to a codebase with multiple services via CI/CD pipeline.
- · Updating and new features, to improve account onboarding tools - including CSV reader, giving admin users the ability to upload csv to do mass-scale updating and creating of new pieces of building plant material within the model, with relevant relationships between them.
- Adding improvements to the front-end working as part as design working group. Wire-framing existing flows to improve UX.

Tech stack:

- Front-end: Vue.js, JQuery, Pyramid, Plotly, Lodash
- · Back-end: Pydantic, Marshmallow, Postgres, SQLAlchemy, Docker

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

Associate Software Engineering Coach

_nology · Oct 2021-Nov2022

- Teaching: Leading 3 4-hour code-along lessons a weeek on core web-dev topics, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React and basic Java on numerous 12- week courses.
- Managing client projects: Leading a team of 15-17 students building a prototype solutions for a real-life client.
- · Hired after showing strong communications skills and good technical understanding on _nology's self-paced course. Promoted from Junior to Associate Coach after just 6 months of coaching experience.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Bootcamp

_nology Oct 2021 - Jan 2022

Self Pace Developer Part-Time Course

_nology Apr 2021- Oct 2021

MSc Comparative Politics

Merit University College London 2016-2017

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

Communications Executive

Imperial Brands
Oct 2018- Oct 2021

- Content creator & writer: Producing regular blogs, infographics, web pages and videos.
- Lead on sections of a major website redesign and launch, working with digital agency.
- Extensive stakeholder management and engagement:
 Delivering content in a highly complex, scrutinised and
 regulated subject area where organisational strategy was
 not always clear.
- Presenting to senior leaders & large functions: Getting buy-in on key comms pla§ns to support scientific ESG initatives, at times presenting to over 200+ attendees.

SOLUTIONS I'VE BUILT



REACT

FIREBASE

VIEW APP ▶

Save Oom

- A desktop web app designed to help children learn phonics and pheonemes.
- Intended for parents to play with their children (ages < 5), the app has multiple games to help children common sounds needed to learn basic literacy.
- I also led on the requirements gathering and writing user stories in the initial design phase for producing an MVP.
 Our prototype allowed the clients, to apply for funding and launch the first tests in schools.